Guide to the United States Bicentennial Committee, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
United States Bicentennial Committee, Yale University, records
1970-1977
RU 714
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.75
(8 boxes)
The records consist of memoranda, subject files, publications, minutes, and related objects documenting the activities and operations of the Yale United States Bicentennial Committee.
Yale University. United States Bicentennial Committee
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 6 (YRG 6), Records of Yale committees.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by type of material.
Biographical / Historical
The committee was formed in 1975 to coordinate Yale University's participation in national and state activities commemorating the bicentennial of the United States of America in 1976. Robin W. Winks, a professor of history, served as chairman of the committee, which disbanded in 1977.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of memoranda, subject files, publications, minutes, and related objects documenting the activities and operations of the Yale United States Bicentennial Committee.
American Revolution Bicentennial, 1976; Winks, Robin W., 1930-; Yale University. United States Bicentennial Committee
- Records, 1970-1977; Accession 1976-A-008
  - Correspondence
    - 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1a)
    - 1975 Jan-Mar (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1975 Apr-May (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1975 Jun (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1975 Jul (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1975 Aug (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1975 Sep (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1975 Oct (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1975 Nov (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1975 Dec, no date (1975) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1976 Jan (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1976 Feb (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1976 Mar (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1976 Apr (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1976 May (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1976 Jun (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1976 Jun-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - no date (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Subject files, including correspondence
    - George W. Pierson
      - 1973, 1974 Jan-May (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - 1974 Jul-Dec (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - 1975 Jan-Apr (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - 1975 May (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - 1975 Jun-Nov, no date (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - 1976 Mar-Apr (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - 1976 Jun (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - George W. Pierson, Yale: A Short History (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Franklin Reception
      - 1975 Oct-Dec, no date (1975) (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - 1976 Jan-Feb, no date (1976) (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - The American Revolution and the Bicentennial - a conference, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - American Revolution Bicentennial Administration, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - American Revolution Bicentennial Commission, 1976 January-March (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - American Revolution Bicentennial Administration, 1976 April- 1977 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - New Haven Bicentennial Council - Connecticut Humanities Council Grant Application, 1975 May 1 (Box 2, Folder 32a)
    - President's Office
      - 1973-1975, no date (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Secretary's Office, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - S and H Foundation, Lectureship Program, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Howland Prize, 1975 November-1977 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Yale University Band, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - American Art, 1750-1800: Towards Independence (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Agendas and minutes of meetings
      - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - 1976 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Bicentennial Committee
    - Subject files, including correspondence
      - Financial files
        - 1974 (Box 2, Folder 42)
        - 1975 (Box 2, Folder 43)
        - 1976-1977, no date (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - American Revolution Bicentennial Administration publications
        - 1976 (Box 3, Folder 45)
        - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 46)
        - 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - American Revolution Bicentennial Commission - Bicentennial Newsletter, Bicentennial Times, 1972-1976 (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - American Revolution Bicentennial Administration/U.S. Government Publications, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - Commercial publications
        - 1974-1975, no date (Box 3, Folder 50)
        - 1974-1976, no date (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Cultural Program Announcements, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Yale publications
      - Yale University Bicentennial Committee, 1976 April (Box 4, Folder 53)
      - American Art: 1750-1800 Towards Independence, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 54)
      - Bicentennial Sixteen Month Calendar, 1976-1976 (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - Yale Alumni Magazine, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Yale Medicine, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - Yale University Cultural Program Announcements, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - Papers delivered at the American Revolution and the Bicentennial Conference, 1975 May (Box 4, Folder 58a)
      - Yale publications, miscellaneous, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - New Haven Publications
      - New Haven Colony Historical Society, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - New Haven Celebrates the Bicentennial, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - New Haven Newsletter, miscellaneous, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - The Connecticut Bicentennial Gazette, 1973-1977 (Box 4a, Folder 63)
      - The Bicentennial in Connecticut 1976, 1977 (Box 4a, Folder 64)
      - Sister Cities International Town Affiliation Program, 1973-1977, undated (Box 4a, Folder 65)
      - Miscellaneous publications, undated (Box 4a, Folder 66 - 69)
      - M. Szabo-Pelsoczi and Associates, The Bicentennial Papers: A Program for American Reconstruction, 1975-1976, undated (Box 4a, Folder 70)
    - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings
      - Yale University, 1973-1976, undated (Box 5, Folder 71)
      - General Bicentennial (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Objects
      - Tape of Robin Winks on Colberg Show (Box 5)
      - 2 Bicentennial buttons (Box 5)
      - Bicentennial pencil (Box 5)
      - 2 Champagne corks (Box 5)
      - Bicentennial knitted lai (Box 5)
      - Certificate of recognition to Yale (Box 7)
      - Printed volume, Bicentennial Times: Commemorative Reprints, published by the American Revolution Bicentennial Administration, all issues of the Bicentennial Times are reprinted in this volume [1977]." (Box 6)